Something that's actually worth clarifying as well,
is that for the naming conventions for the branches,
basically every section will have three parts.
There will be the section number.
So in this case, we're in section two.
So be O2-begin, so there's the where we start.
And then we have the exercise that accompanies with it.
We'll be O2-exercise, and that's like the starting point.
And then when we wrap up and we've coded along
and done everything, that will be your O2 finish.
And then we move on each section that way.
And so just know that that's the convention
for how the exercises and code tracking is working.
OK, so now that we've talked about props
with the option API, it's time to get into something
a little bit more media, which is like all the other fundamentals
that come with the option API.
So when we go to the restaurant page,
we'll see here that we have this restaurant list.
And the nice thing about view three being rewritten with TypeScript
is that a lot of inference is happening
kind of a little bit more automatically.
So you'll notice that restaurant list
does have like what it's inferring from the given object.
But at this point, we have no way of really telling it
that like, hey, this is something that we want
to actually be of type restaurant.
And so now we have another problem, though,
is that as we just did inside a restaurant card,
we have our type being defined in a different file.
So the question, of course, the first thing we need to learn
is how do we share those types between the files?
And so the easiest way to do this, especially when
you're getting started out, is to create a types file
right at the root of the source.
So I'll just call it types.ts.
Now you'll see some other folder conventions
where people have a folder of types
and then they break it out into different modules.
And that's for when you scale and you have the types
to support that.
I don't think it needs to jump into that immediately.
So let's just keep it simple and we have a type file
right here.
And so let me actually close this real quick.
And let me bump this over so you can see the side by side.
So all we're going to do is we're going to take this type restaurant
that we define.
We're going to cut and paste it over here.
And then if you're new to like doing modules
and that kind of thing within JavaScript, all we need to do
is basically tell it that we want to export the thing out of the file.
And so in this case, we're exploring the type of restaurant.
Now when we save this and save this, this is a good thing.
Because what are we seeing?
We see an error.
Because it says, hey, you're referencing this type restaurant
I've never seen it.
So how do we import it?
Similar to before, just like we do a pro-type,
we insert a pro-type of restaurant.
Now in my case, it's actually doing an auto-complete,
but sometimes you need to actually just type it out the first time
and then it'll know to do that.
But when I hit enter, you'll notice that it's
automatically then importing restaurant from the type
it's recognized it.
And so if you're also wondering about this alias here,
if you're new, this is basically a build alias
let you know to go straight to the root.
Because sometimes when you have a lot of nested folders,
you get a lot of this, trying to figure out where the root is.
And so this alias here is just the way to make your life
a little bit easier.
OK.
So now that we have that, we now have the ability
to use the restaurant type across multiple files.
So let's go ahead and go on to restaurants page
and see how that might work.
So the first thing we need, we're taking a look at this,
we say, OK, we have this data object here that has all this
reactive data, we need to actually define what the shape of it
looks like.
More importantly, we need to learn how to actually
say, hey, how do we define this as an array?
And so typically, let's just go ahead and let's just do a type
called data shape real quick.
And so we know that filter text is a string.
And then restaurant lists here, if you were to think back
to how we typically define prop types, you might be tempted
to go like, oh, it's like array.
Or you might be like, oh, maybe it's capital A array.
That's not how our arrays are defined in type script.
The way we do that is we actually define what values we expect
inside of the array first.
So in case in the event that it's in array of strings,
we would say string, and then we would have the square brackets.
And that tells you that it's an array of strings.
And so what do we want?
We want an array of restaurants.
So how do we do that?
Well, we're going to import type restaurant.
Is that actually coming up?
Looks like it's not coming up for me this time.
But that's OK.
We'll do it like this.
And so there we go.
And then now we can go ahead and do restaurant like this.
Save import type.
Oh, huh.
This is where red squiggly lines are a lot are very helpful.
Is we haven't actually converted this file over to TypeScript yet.
That's why it's yelling at us.
And that's probably actually why my autocomplete
wasn't even working.
So let's go ahead and make restaurants page and add
the TypeScript attribute to it.
And then we need to make sure just like before,
we'll go through an import defined component.
And then let's go ahead and wrap our default object
with that defined component bit.
Scroll down.
Wrap.
This is not right, but I'll fix that later.
Do you do do do?
And then I can end with the TX extension.
OK, there we go.
And so see, like the red squiggly line is super helpful.
And that's what we want our code editor to do for us, right?
It's front load that stuff.
Because while hot modular reloading has been great,
it's still one more step to have to go to your browser
realize something's broken.
And then switch back to your code editor
to figure out what's going on.
And so now we see here that we have OK, we have this shape.
We have this restaurant list that has a bunch of restaurants.
And so actually, we have one more property
I believe in our data, we do.
We have this show new form bit.
So let me go ahead and add show new form.
And this is a Boolean.
And so we didn't go through this explicitly,
but I have assumed some basic knowledge
of JavaScript-primitive types, so that all the things
we're seeing here, string number, Boolean,
these are just basically standard within JavaScript.
It's nothing custom about this so far.
But we have learned the custom syntax for a rate.
And that's an important one that you'll probably
are using a lot.
So now that we have this, we
did actually tell the shape, what's the shape of the data
like?
And so this brings us to a question that
actually saw in the chat, which is, you'll
notice that I'm using an error function for the data property.
Just for context, what some of you may be used to, actually,
is let me just delete this real quick,
just to make it a little bit easier.
If you may be used to it, actually, being defined this way.
So it's data as a function with this syntax,
and then there's literally an object that's being returned.
So it's a little bit longer.
There's no right or wrong.
It's just that this other syntax is just a little bit more
compact.
There we go.
Personally, I prefer the error function,
because it's not that you're trying to do anything
like setting up or anything within the function
where you need to use it before you return.
And so this is a cleaner way of just
getting it done in one minute.
OK, so when it comes to defining things in TypeScript,
you want to basically say what is being returned,
because that's what we ultimately care about.
And so what we can do here is we can basically
add a colon here and see that we want
to return this shape of data.
And so that's really what sure ultimately saying,
is that inside of here, you're going to have a shape.
And what's that shape of data?
Well, we have filter tags, a restaurant list,
which has a bunch of restaurants.
And so you can see here that now, when you hover over
a restaurant list, it actually inherits all the properties
that come within it.
So now, I'm not sure of this or yell at me just yet.
So this here is one of the things that
TypeScript makes our lives a lot better,
is that if someone tries to randomly add this property here,
hello message, you'll notice here that it's saying,
hey, by the way, I was expecting this.
And instead, you gave me this instead.
And so actually, I totally forgot.
But you'll notice that here, this hover,
some of you might have seen this because this
is a VS code extension.
I believe it's called typeScriptR translator.
Oh, gosh, I think there's a map for a cock
who might have had that one.
Yes, okay, this one.
TypeScriptR translator, it's a great one to download,
because it's basically an open source effort
by the team or by the team, by the community
to make TypeScript errors a little bit more readable.
So that you're not just reading through just like,
mumbo jumbo.
And so basically, as you see here live,
it's like, hey, this is the error message you normally get.
And then the community says,
this is how we think it what it means in plain language.
Super super helpful when working with TypeScript.
But anyhow, okay, so this is how we know our,
basically, this is how we define types on our data
is by defining it in advance as this sort of data shape.
I call it data shape rather than just data
because data is such a charge word.
I think in a lot of things, so when you're searching for things,
so given that it's a shape of the data,
I just call it data shape.